Matt Taylor

1010 Central Ave St Petersburg, FL 33705

727 537 0413

maylortaylor@gmail.com maylortaylor.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled Full Stack Developer with 6+ years of experience in a real world work environment. I work well in a team environment, and am seasoned enough to accomplish projects with minimal direction and oversight. I am looking for a position with opportunity for growth, including leading a team of my own and learning new skills and languages.

SKILLS

- ScrumMaster Certified (CSM)
- 5+ years with SQL and MySQL databases, C# language, Razor templates, and MVC framework
- 5+ years using .NET 4.6 and 4.7
- 4+ years of AngularJS development, Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS/LESS
- 2+ years using CosmosDb and the latest .NET Core and .NET Standard technologies and builds
- 2+ years experience with Node, Express, MEAN stack, and Angular 2+
- Well versed on proper RESTful standards, HTML5 standards, ADA compliance standards, and C# coding patterns such as the "Visitor Pattern" and the "Repository Pattern"
- 1 year with PHP Laravel framework
- 6 months with Flutter phone app development

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer, Bovsi Studios

St Petersburg, Florida — Sept. 2018-present

Working with Bovsi Studios, an Agile development group focusing on mobile app development, enterprise software, and web development, helped me learn the business-side of client-based app/website development. Before I joined the company, Bovsi Studios had an established business of Wordpress development. When I joined, they were making the move into app development. I helped the company develop numerous web apps, phone apps, and took the lead on their Wordpress development.

Accomplishments

- Obtained <u>ScrumMaster Certification (CSM)</u>
- Developed numerous phone apps using Google's cross-platform development framework <u>Flutter.io</u>
- Lead a team of developers that created .NETCore web apps

Full Stack Developer, Presence.io

St Petersburg, Florida — Sep. 2014-Aug. 2018

My first year and half at Presence (formerly Check I'm Here) involved me and a Senior Developer re-architecting an MVP application. The application we designed was a .NETCORE C# MVC Framework web app with a SQL database, AngularJS 1.6 front-end framework using the component-router and Typescript, and a C# RESTful API with the repository pattern design.

During my time with the company, I was the lead developer for the company's mobile API and the go-to developer for general C# or SQL questions. I worked

closely with the customer service team to help test the system's UI and APIs. I also worked with the CEO / product owner on a daily basis to gather requirements for new features and define business logic for existing features. I also helped upgrade and maintain the Node.js application that our customer service team used internally.

Accomplishments

- Created numerous Powershell scripts to migrate data from one SQL database to another
- Helped build SQL tables, scripts, CRUD operations, and server-side repositories for controlling the SQL database
- Created CosmosDb CRUD operations in C# repositories
- Developed and maintained APIs used by the company's mobile phone apps
- Created C# services and processes using the "Visitor Pattern"
- Trained and taught new developers on the details of the APIs and web apps
- Had over 400,000 lines of code committed to production

IT Administrator/Backend Developer, Applied Technology Resources Inc.

Seminole, Florida-Nov. 2012-Sept. 2014

I was the IT administrator handling tasks such as creating new employee accounts, preparing computers for new users, doing general Windows repairs on employees' computers, and troubleshooting the network.

Due to my skill set I was able to transition this into a more senior role creating queries for the SQL and MySQL databases, updating/repairing custom written .NET C# and VB programs, updating/maintaining the Microsoft Access program that employees used, and creating various applications that helped the company's processes.

Accomplishments

- Created an OCR (optical character recognition) application in C# that would read scanned files for useful information such as addresses and names
- Created a Raspberry PI project in Python to be used as a card reader.
 This was used to lock/unlock certain doors based on the employee's access level.

EDUCATION

University of Alabama

Bachelor of Science Degree in Marketing/Business — 2007-2011

During my time at The University of Alabama I took 1.5 years of computer programming classes. I finished my Marketing/Business Degree with a 3.5 GPA.

IT-WORCS Scholarship awarded Fall 2009